#### Contact

suhas.anand@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/suhasanand (LinkedIn)

www.suhasanand.com (Personal)

#### Top Skills

Business Strategy
Deal Structuring
Sustainable Development

Languages English

# **Suhas Anand**

Building a more inclusive, sustainable world; Country Head at ShARE

Dubai

## Summary

Building an exciting startup, ShARE, a virtual, not-for-profit university in the field of education, leadership development, and advisory focused on building a more sustainable, equitable world.

Previously Associate Partner and Leader Client development (MENA) for McKinsey and Company.

~16+ years of experience working with CXOs and governments in forming and executing growth strategies, valuing assets and counselling on deals/risk management

(13+ years of consulting experience with McKinsey & Co.in Asia, Middle East, US and Europe. 3+ years line experience managing teams of engineers in Infrastructure & Energy space in Asia and Africa)

Education: B Tech Mechanical engineering (National Institute of Technology, India), MBA (Indian Institute of Management, Ahmedabad, India)

Specialties: Startup, Not for profit, Education, Ed Tech, E mobility, Energy (oil & gas, utilities), Renewable energy, Solar, Water and waste water, Gas pricing and economics, Sustainable development/infra, Infrastructure/Real estate

## Experience

ShARE - Growing a new generation of leaders Head, India and Middle East August 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month) Dubai,UAE and Bengaluru, India

I head ShARE in India & ME. We are building a not-for-profit start-up focused on developing a new generation of leaders who would do well for themselves

Page 1 of 3

AND do good for society. I also advise & train corporate and government leaders on building sustainable companies and countries apart from continuing to teach ShARE students when ever time permits.

McKinsey & Company
Associate Partner
June 2006 - July 2019 (13 years 2 months)
Dubai, Mumbai, New Delhi

Head- Client development for MENA clients in Energy (conventional and renewable) and Infrastructure sectors. Consultant to CXOs and government leaders / heads in Asia, Middle East, Europe and US across Infrastructure, Oil & Gas, Real estate, Renewable energy

In my corporate client work , I supported large companies in using data analytics & market modeling to shape their strategies, helped redesign organisations and advised on leadership development at CXO levels.

In my public sector work, I helped major economies/Kingdoms in ME transition into a more sustainable energy mix, defined partnership strategies with IOCs / global majors, value resource potential (esp oil & gas reserves), build sustainable infras & transportation sectors.

Within McKinsey, I conceptualized, built and led ME focused Energy Analytics modelling suite. (Suite of integrated optimization models across upstream, midstream, downstream of energy sector - both conventional and alternate energy sources)

Larsen & Toubro Limited
Project manager, Energy and Infrastructure
May 2001 - July 2004 (3 years 3 months)
Mumbai, Dar es Salaam

I managed projects across infrastructure, offshore oil & gas, onshore refining, gas power plants etc.

Founding team member of East Africa office based out of Dar-es-Salaam, Tanzania.

Selected to L&T's prestigious Global Leadership Program.

### Education

Indian Institute of Management, Ahmedabad
PGDBM / MBA equivalent, Finance, Strategy · (2004 - 2006)

National Institute of Technology Calicut

B.Tech, Mechanical Engineering · (1997 - 2001)

Kendriya Vidyalaya

School, science · (1987 - 1997)